Uh
I can say welcome brothers and sisters
to another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother Tanzil.
>> Brother Tanzil.
And God spake all these words saying,
I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything
that is in heaven above, or that is in
the earth beneath, or that is in the
water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them.
For I the Lord thy God am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquities of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation
of them that hate me, and showing mercy
unto thousands of them that love me, and
keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day, to
keep it holy. Six days shalt thou labor
and do all thy work.
But the seventh day is the Sabbath of
the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt not
do any work, thou, nor thy son,
nor thy daughter,
thy manservant, nor thy maidservant, nor
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates. For in six days the
Lord made heaven and earth,
the sea, and all that in them is, and
rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it.
Honor thy father and thy mother, that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee.
Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery.
Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
house.
wife.
Nor his manservant, nor his maidservant,
nor his ox, nor his ass, nor anything
that is thy neighbor's.
We read Exodus 20:1-17,
and may the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his words. In Jesus' name we
pray.
Amen.
So, here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and the
long scripture questions, as well as
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate, we are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But, let me
introduce you to family on the panel
this evening. We got brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother Julius. Good evening, everybody.
Brother Tanzel. Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Shawn.
And we have the guest caller with us,
and I'm brother Cornell.
So, Sister Deborah, before we begin this
evening, I just wanted to give a quick
announcement that we are in our Black
History Series, and coming up this
Saturday at the Israel of God Bible
Study Class, February the 14th will be
our second session titled Slavery. So,
please come out to join us and find out
about the true history.
With that being said, sister Deborah
Woody is our first question of the
evening.
Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Be
alert as in Psalms 1 10
verse 7, can you please explain this
scripture and lift up thy head?
All right, and that's coming out of
Psalms 1 10 and 7 10. Let's go there,
read that and then the guest caller will
take it from there.
He shall drink of the brook in the way.
Therefore, shall he lift up the head.
And when I looked at it, there ain't
nothing to explain. He told you
point-blank. He's either going to drink
out of brook and he's going to lift up
his head.
If there ain't nothing to it, I can't
see it.
There's no scripture.
Break it down. It's just simple. It mean
what it say.
Don't have to say.
All right, we're going to leave it right
there. Hope that shed some light for you
as we move to our next one.
Next one, Valencia says, can you tell me
when Jesus started his way down on the
mount and it split east and west, was
that before he touched the mount or
after he touched it in his power and
Zechariah 14:4
and 5 are given?
Zechariah 14:4 and 5, the splitting of
the mount.
Brother Jerome.
Let's go read the verses uh, Zechariah
14:4 and 5.
And his feet shall stand in that day
upon the mount of olives, which is
before Jerusalem on the east.
And the mount of olives shall cleave in
two in the midst thereof toward the east
and toward the west. And there shall be
a very great valley. And half of the
mount shall remove toward the north and
half of it toward the south. Okay, stop
right there.
Right there and mean what it say. It
said, when his feet shall stand on that
mountain, that's when it's going to
split. But I understand that ain't
happened yet cuz the Lord don't come
until
after the great tribulation. All right,
so
uh, but keep reading.
And ye shall flee to the valley of the
mountains. For the valley of the
mountains shall reach unto Azal.
Yea, ye shall flee like as ye fled from
before the earthquake in the days of
Uzziah, king of Judah.
And the Lord my God shall come and all
the saints with thee. Okay, so we can go
to, uh,
Thessalonians, 1 Thessalonians and it
kind of tells you when he's going to
start
his, uh, descent.
You know, uh, according to your
question.
When he start his way down, let's go
read that 1 Thessalonians chapter 4.
And we can pick it up at the 16.
And I'll read to the 17.
When you get it, go ahead.
For the Lord himself shall descend from
heaven with the shout,
with the voice of the archangel, and
with the trump of God. And the dead in
Christ shall rise first.
Then we which are alive and remain shall
be caught up together with them in the
clouds to meet the Lord in the air. And
so shall we ever be with the Lord. Yeah,
so that tie with that Zechariah that we
just read, verse 4 and 5.
Yeah, and we know when that seventh
trumpet blow, the Lord going to be on
his way down. And when that seventh
trumpet blow,
then
that angel going to give the shout, and
we going to meet the Lord in the air.
Okay.
Yeah. But yeah, that mountain split as
soon as the Lord's uh feet hit it,
that's when it's going to split. It's
going to split north, south, east, and
west.
That's all I got.
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. Hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next question.
Moving on, Sky Rider wants to know what
does the temple of God uh mean in 1
Corinthians 3:16
and 17?
1 Corinthians 3:16 and 17, what does the
temple of God mean, brother Julius?
Let's go and read that, Tenzel.
And let's look and and we going to let
the Bible tell you yourself what it
means.
When you get it, 1 Corinthians 3:16 and
17. Pay attention to what you're
reading. Read it slow. Go ahead,
brother.
Know ye not that ye are the temple of
God,
and that the spirit of God dwelleth in
you? You are the temple of God. Go
ahead.
If any man defile the temple of God,
him shall God destroy.
For the temple of God is holy,
which temple ye are. Let's turn right
over to 1 Corinthians, the sixth
chapter, and let Paul tell you plainly.
1 Corinthians
and we going
to pick it up at verse 19 20.
He's going to tell you plainly what you
are. Go ahead.
What?
Know you not that your body is the
temple of the Holy Ghost
which is in you?
Which you have of God?
And you are not your own.
For you are bought with a price.
Therefore, glorify God in your body and
in your spirit which are God's. So, now,
your body, which is you, are the temple
of God and the Holy Spirit that's
dwelling in you is the word of God.
But, you can defile yourself by your
behavior, your thoughts, and your
actions, sisters and brothers. That's
why you are bought with the shed blood
of Jesus. He purchased you
with his blood. So, you are not on your
own. You just can't
uh live your life recklessly because
that's how you defile yourself that
departing from the law, statutes, and
commandments of the living God. So, the
answer is you are the temple of God and
the temp the word of God is in you.
And you got to walk circumspectly so
that
how you going to destroy you? If you
defile your body, your behaviors, your
ways,
he going to destroy you in the lake of
fire. That's all I got.
All right.
>> So,
let's walk righteously before the Lord.
All right. I'm going to move on to our
next one.
Next one. D law asked, "Who are the two
houses of Israel in Isaiah 8 verse 14?"
Isaiah 8 and 14, the two houses
of Israel.
Go right ahead, brother Gerald.
Let's go read the verse. Um
Isaiah chapter 8 verse 14.
And he shall be for a sanctuary,
but for a stone of stumbling, and for a
rock of offense
to both the house of Israel,
for a gin and for a snare to the
inhabitants of Jerusalem.
Okay. Uh the two houses
uh of Israel,
uh they they became that way when it was
split.
When God had the house of Israel split
into two houses, okay, after the death
of Solomon.
Uh the nine tribes, that was considered
the house that was called Israel, and
the three tribes
uh were considered the house
of Judah, okay?
So, let's go to Ezekiel chapter 37.
And we're going to pick it up at verse
21 and read to the 22 and we're going to
skip.
Ezekiel 37 verse 21 and 22.
You get it, go ahead and read.
And say unto them, Thus saith the Lord
God, Behold, I will take the children of
Israel from among the heathen, whither
they be gone,
and will gather them on every side, and
bring them into their own land.
And I will make them one nation in the
land upon the mountains of Israel, and
one king shall be
king to them all. And they shall be no
more two nations, neither shall they be
divided into two kingdoms any more at
all. Yeah, so Lord going to put them
back together and make them one nation
again, but right now
they split into two. You got nine
tribes, what they call the northern
kingdom, and you got the three tribes,
Benjamin, Levi, and Judah, they call the
southern kingdom. But, skip up and read
verse 16.
Moreover, thou son of man, take thee one
stick, and write upon it for Judah, and
for the children of Israel, his
companions. All right, that's them the
three tribes I just them his companions,
them three tribes I just mentioned.
Judah, Benjamin, and Levi. Go ahead.
Then take another stick and write upon
it, for Joseph, the stick of Ephraim,
and for all the house of Israel, his
companions. All right, so those are the
rest of the tribes, which is nine of
them. They under the stick of Israel.
Mhm. Head tribe being Ephraim, that's
why it mentioned he Ephraim in that
verse.
All right, which is one of the sons of
uh
Joseph, if I'm if I'm not mistaken.
Okay. All right, but uh
uh so, you can read about that uh
uh Jeremiah, we ain't going to go there,
but in your own time, go to Jeremiah 50,
and then you'll read about who took out
the nine tribes, uh which were the
Assyrians, and then you can uh
uh read about the Babylonians under
Nebuchadnezzar that took out the three
tribes. You can read that 50:17-20.
That's all I got on.
All right. Thank you for that. Hopefully
that answered your question as we move
on to our next one.
Next one, MC says, "My husband just
found out by DNA he has a daughter. She
is 50 now, and he is 75 with health
issues. According to the Bible, is he
responsible for her at this age?"
He discovered he got a daughter
in his later years, is he still
responsible for her? Brother Dre, what
you say?
Absolutely, he is responsible for his
daughter.
Um
as a wife,
you being his wife,
and him having health issues, I
understand you being concerned
about him and his well-being.
And his daughter being 50 years old,
you know, that's that's being without a
father for 50 years.
And when he found out that he had a
daughter, it would behoove him to do
what a father would do for his child.
Let's go over to uh 1
Timothy, the fifth chapter. 1 Timothy,
the fifth chapter.
And we going to read verse 8.
1 Timothy 5, verse 8. Read that when you
get it, Tenzel.
But if any provide not for his own,
especially for those of his own house,
he have denied the faith and is worse
worse than an infidel.
So, at 50 years old, she's a grown
woman. So, what can he provide for her?
He can provide
knowledge, emotional support,
relationship that she hasn't had in 50
years,
some multitude of things that he can
provide that she needs and probably he
needs. At 75,
it doesn't matter. It's important. It's
a blessing that he has come
to know his that he has a daughter
and and to come to that knowledge. Let's
go to one other place. Let's go to Luke
15.
Luke 15.
And we going to pick it up at verse 11.
Luke 15 and verse 11. Read that when you
get there, brother.
15, verse 11.
And he said, "A certain man had two
sons. Mhm. And the younger of them said
to his father, "Father, give me the
portion of goods
that to me.
And he divided unto them his living.
And not many days after the younger son
gathered all together and took his
journey to a far country,
and there wasted his substance with
riotous living.
And when he had spent all, there arose a
mighty famine in the land,
and he began to be in want. Now, this
son,
the father gave him his wages, but
his father
absolutely was worried about his son.
And
his son wasted the money and spent it
all, and and when the famine came, he
began to want, and you can read the rest
of it, but it talks about him
eating
what the pigs was eating out of the
trough, and then he came to himself.
Skip down to verse 23 and read that,
brother.
And bring hither the fatted calf, and
kill it. And let us eat and be merry.
Now, wait a minute. After he came to
himself,
he came back to his father and said,
"Hey, I I've done
wrong, you know. Let me just work like a
servant." And his father, this is what
his father did.
His father killed the fatted calf. Read
it again, brother. Go ahead.
And bring hither the fatted calf, and
kill it.
And let us eat and be merry. Mhm.
For this my son was dead, and is alive
again. Mhm. Was lost, and is found.
And they began to be merry.
My son was lost and is found. Now, this
is not
you know, the same situation, but yet
here's a daughter
that may have been looking for her
father.
Right.
You know, for 50 years. She may have
children and he got grandchildren.
Right.
>> So, it's an opportunity.
You know, but this father when his son
came back
he killed the fatted calf and he was
excited about it and then it goes on to
tell you
that his his older brother
had a problem with it. Skip down and
read verse 28 and 29.
And he was angry and would not go in.
Therefore, came his father out and
entreated him.
And he answered him saying to his
father, "Lo, these many years do I serve
thee.
Neither transgress
I at any time thy commandment.
And yet thou never gavest me a kid that
I might make merry with my friends.
He said, "Hey, you didn't give you
didn't give me a kid that I make merry
with my friends and I've been here with
you the whole time."
But listen at the wisdom of the father
here. Skip down to verse 31, brother,
and read that.
And he said unto him, "Son, thou art
ever with me.
And all that I have is thine. Mhm.
It was meet that we should make merry
and be glad. For this thy brother was
dead and is alive again
and was lost and is found."
Now, she found out that her father is
alive
and she's 50 years old and he's 75.
As a wife
I would definitely encourage that
relationship.
Mhm. That's all I got.
Yeah.
All right, brother.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
their question as we move on to our next
Next one. You all asked
for you to expound on Isaiah 44 verses 6
through 8. Why is God saying he is alone
as in several other scriptures? It
sounds absolute.
Well, he was speaking in terms of
himself.
And that he is a God that created
everything. So, when it comes to all the
other gods, hey, he's the only one that
matter. But, let's go to that Isaiah 44
and read that verse 6 through 8.
Cuz he's going to even tell us that,
hey, when it come to any other God that
might matter, he said he don't even know
any. Pick it up at 6, brother. Go ahead.
Thus saith the Lord, the King of Israel
and his Redeemer, the Lord of hosts.
I am the first and I am the last and
besides me, there is no God. Uh, we
talking about the God family right there
in 6. Keep going.
And who, as I shall call,
and shall declare it
and set it in order for me, since I
appointed the ancient people and the
things that are coming and shall come,
let them show unto them.
Yeah.
But, fear ye not neither be afraid.
Have not I told thee from that time?
And have declared it?
Ye are even my witnesses.
Is there a God beside me?
Yeah, there is no God.
I know not any.
So, when he's speaking about there is no
God he know not any, he is talking about
himself here. But, we know and we're
going to show you that he wasn't the
only one that's in the God family. But,
let's go to Psalms 96 right quick.
Psalms 96 and pick it up at that verse 4
when you get there. Psalms 96 and 4. Cuz
this is what he was saying when he say,
"I know not any when it comes to these
other gods."
Psalms 96 and 4. Go ahead, brother.
For the Lord is great and greatly to be
praised.
He is to be feared above all gods. Mhm.
For all the gods of the nations are
idols.
But the Lord made the heavens.
Yep. Go ahead. Honor and majesty are
before him. And strength and beauty are
in his sanctuary.
Yes. Give unto the Lord, oh ye kindreds
of the people. Give unto the Lord glory
and strength.
Give unto the Lord the glory due unto
his name.
And bring an offering and come into his
courts. So, you see the Lord is letting
you know that he's only God that got all
this power on his resume. But let's go
to Isaiah 57 to show that he is not the
only God in the God family. Isaiah 57,
brother.
And when you get there,
read that one verse
15. Because the same God we just read
about in that Isaiah 44 and 6, let's see
where he sits and who sits beside him.
Verse 15. Go ahead.
But thus saith the high and lofty one,
that inhabiteth eternity,
whose name is holy.
I dwell in the high and holy place with
him.
Also that is of a contrite and humble
spirit. Yeah. To revive the spirit of
the humble,
and to revive the heart of the contrite
ones. So, he was saying that he sit
right beside the Father. So, we know
that he is not the only God in the God
family. There's only two. But when he
spoke in that Isaiah, he was saying that
hey, when it comes to all those other
gods, hey, he is the only one that
matters. That's right.
So, that's all I got on that.
And we hope that that answered your
question as we continue to keep moving.
Uh moving on,
Brick Brack says, "People like to use
Genesis 1:28
to justify them having multiple kids
with several people. Did this only apply
to Adam, Eve, and Noah?
And does this instruction still stand
till this day to reproduce?"
A couple of questions inside a couple of
questions, Brother Julius, but please
shed some light.
First of all,
this does not justify
uh having multiple women
and and reproducing children because
who going to take care of all them
children?
Let's look at what the book says.
Look at what the book says.
Genesis chapter
and uh the she said they use
uh Let's read verse 28.
And God blessed them. And God said unto
them,
"Be fruitful and multiply, and replenish
the earth, and subdue it, and have
dominion over the fish of the sea, and
over the fowls of the air, and over
every living thing that moveth upon the
earth." Now, that is ongoing, and that
is the protocol for man to follow.
For man to follow so that
uh people uh uh
be born.
But the Lord also said, "Do all things
decent and in order," didn't he?
Mhm. Yeah. Let's look at what the order
is.
Genesis chapter 2, and let's pick this
up. Genesis 2
and pick it up at Let's get back to the
matter of it and verse 22. Go ahead and
read.
Genesis 2:22 Yes, sir. And the rib which
the Lord God had taken from man made he
a woman and
>> Made he women. Made he women.
a woman Go ahead.
and brought her unto the man Uh-huh.
And Adam said, "This is now bone of my
bones and flesh of my flesh.
She shall be called woman because she
was taken out of man. Go ahead.
Therefore shall a man leave his father
and his mother and shall cleave unto his
wife. That's w i f e, wife, one. Go
ahead.
And they shall be one flesh. So now,
that is husband and wife and the purpose
of marriage is to reproduce, to continue
the protocol of what God gave man in
Genesis 1:28.
Let's go to Deuteronomy 17.
Deuteronomy 17 and we going to pick this
up at verse 15.
It's out of the mouth of the Lord. The
Lord had Moses write this. Then it's
Deuteronomy 17 and picking it up at
verse 15, Tenzel. Go ahead and read.
Thou shalt in no wise set him king over
thee
whom the Lord thy God shall choose. One
from among thy brethren shall thou set
king over thee and thou mayest not set a
stranger over thee which is not of thy
brother. What should he What should he
not do at verse 17?
Neither shall he multiply wives to
himself. Multiply means more than one.
So people say, "Well, that's for the
king." No, so go to king, so go to
people.
Finish it up.
That is how our turn not away neither
shall he greatly multiply to himself
silver and gold. Because if you have uh
um multiple wives, you going to have
multiple children.
And who going to take care of all them
children?
Let's go to first to my last place.
First Corinthians chapter 7.
Cuz you cannot use that to justify that.
>> [clears throat]
>> First Corinthians
7 and pick it up at two. We let's go two
to five quickly. Go ahead.
Nevertheless, to avoid fornication, let
every man have his own wife. W I F E
One wife. Go ahead. And let every woman
have her own husband. Uh-huh. And the
husband render unto the wife due
benevolence. And likewise also the wife
unto the husband. One wife.
Adam had one wife. He set the protocol.
And the Lord tell him we reading the the
New Testament. Paul is telling you the
same thing. Let every man and even if
you go other route, it will tell you a
bishop or deacon must be the husband of
one wife. You cannot use Genesis 1:28 to
justify having multiple women and
reproducing all these children. Who
going to take care of them? That's all I
got.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered their question as we move on
with the time check to our next.
Yes, the time is 8:01. Uh Talitha
Woosley has two questions. The first is
first she asked, does Ezekiel 44:1-3
prove that Mary was a virgin before and
after Christ? And second, she also
states, my husband says brother and
sister is also used loosely and is the
same as saying "kinsmen". Is this true?
All right, this question begins in
Ezekiel 44
verses 1 through 3.
Tanzil, so when you get there, read it.
Guest caller, we'll take it from there.
Then he brought me back the way of the
gate. It's Ezekiel 44.
Yes, sir.
>> Yes.
Then he brought me back the way of the
gate of the outward sanctuary which
looked toward the east, and it was shut.
Then said the Lord unto me,
"This gate shall be shut. It shall not
be open, and no man shall enter in by it
because the Lord, the God of Israel,
have entered in by it. Therefore, it
shall be shut.
It is for the prince.
The prince, he shall sit in it to eat
bread before the Lord.
He shall enter by the way of the porch
of that gate, and shall go out
by the way of the same."
So, her question there, uh
she asked, "Does that prove that Mary
was a virgin before and after Christ?"
Guest caller.
Guest caller, you with us?
All right, might be a little
technical difficulty going on there. So,
Sister Deborah, let's move to our next
question, and we'll come back to that
one.
Uh sure.
Oh, okay, you with us, guest caller?
Yeah.
All right, so that uh Ezekiel 44:1-3,
Deborah, what is the question?
Yes, the question again cuz she has two.
The first question is in Ezekiel 44:1,
2, and 3, does that prove that Mary was
a virgin before and after Christ?
It has absolutely nothing to do
with Jesus one way or the other before
after the Christ before after him.
Absolutely nothing.
What's the next one?
And her second question she states
uh that my husband says brother and
sister uh uh
brother and sister is also used loosely
and is the same as saying kinsman. Is
this true?
No, you have two type brothers and
sisters. You have biological brothers
and sisters
>> [clears throat]
>> but the brothers and sisters that are in
the Lord call themselves brothers and
sisters because they walk in the Lord.
Go to Matthew the 12th chapter.
I'm reading verses 46
and 50 50.
Matthew 12:46 and 50.
46 through 50.
While he yet spake to the people behold,
his mother and his brethren stood
without desiring to speak with them.
Then one said unto him,
behold, thy mother and thy brother stand
without desiring to speak with thee.
And he answered and said unto him that
told him,
who is my mother and who is who are my
brother?
And he stretched forth his hand toward
his disciples and said, behold,
my mother
and my brother.
For whosoever shall do the will of my
father which is in heaven,
the same
is my brother and sister
and mother."
Well, that's what That's what when you
see the sisters and brothers saying,
"Brother this and brother that and
sister this and sister that." They have
no biological connection.
How can they be kinfolk? But what they
have is a spiritual connection
in the word of God.
Anybody All of us that walked in the
word of God, we are sisters and
brothers.
So, they have to say.
All right. Hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next
question.
Uh next one. Yosuf asked, "What
scriptures in the Old Testament makes
reference to God saying when he brought
the first begotten
into the world, let the angels of God
worship him?"
All right. Now, he's asking what
scripture is in the Old Testament makes
reference to God saying when he brought
the first begotten into the world
that all the angels worship him. Yes,
caller.
It didn't say that. It is not said in
the Old Testament.
It says in the New Testament.
That is Hebrew 1 and 6. Go read.
Hebrews 1
and verse
6.
And again,
when he bringing when he bringeth in the
first begotten into the world,
he said, "And let all the angels of God
worship him."
And that's the only place it says it in
the whole Bible.
It's not written in the Old Testament.
That's it.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next question.
Moving on, uh Skywriter asks, "Would a
person with a
a reprobate mind know if they have it,
or would they even care?"
Well,
let's open that question up to the
panel.
Someone who has a reprobate mind,
do they know if they have it, or would
they even care?
No, they don't know if they have it.
And And so, how How could you know
if you if How could you care if you you
don't know you have it?
Because these are people
that hold the righteousness of God, hold
the word of God in unrighteousness.
And God will turn them over to it. So,
first, let's go into um
Let's go into Romans 1
and start reading at verse 18.
Romans 1, verse 18.
Mhm.
For the wrath of God is revealed from
heaven against all ungodliness and
unrighteousness of men,
who hold the truth in unrighteousness.
Because that which
>> me uh
It lets you know that they knew what the
truth was. Yes. But they didn't deal
with it right. It was unrighteousness.
So, God dealt with them. Keep reading.
Keep reading.
Because that which may be known of God
is manifested in them.
For God has showed it unto them.
For the invisible things of him from the
creation of the world are clearly seen.
Being understood by the things that are
made,
even his eternal power and Godhead.
So that they are without excuse.
Because that when they knew God,
they glorified him not as God, neither
were thankful,
but became vain in their imaginations,
and their foolish heart was darkened.
Professing themselves to be wise, they
became fools.
And changed the glory of their un-
Go ahead.
And changed the glory of the
uncorruptible God into an image made
like to corruptible men,
and to birds and four-footed beasts and
creeping things.
Wherefore God also gave them up to
uncleanness through the lusts of their
own hearts,
to dishonor their own bodies between
themselves.
Who changed the truth of God into a lie,
and worshipped and served the creature
more than the creator,
who is blessed forever. Amen.
For this cause God gave them up into
vile affections.
For even their women did change their
natural use into that which is against
nature.
And likewise also the men leaving the
natural use of the woman, burned in
their lust one towards another.
Men with men working that which is
unseemly, and receiving in themselves
that recompense of their error which was
meet.
And even as they did not like to retain
God in their knowledge, God gave them
over to a reprobate mind, to do those
things which are not convenient.
Now, I'mma show you how God do this.
Now, they didn't want to so
they didn't want to deal with the truth,
but they sold out to a lie. So God
turned them over to a reprobate mind.
How did he do this?
Let's go into 2 Thessalonians the 2nd
chapter.
We're going to start reading at verse 8.
We're going to read from 8 to 12.
Give scriptures 2 Thessalonians.
2nd chapter. Mhm. 2nd chapter verse 8 to
12.
And then shall that wicked be revealed
whom the Lord shall consume with the
spirit of his mouth and shall destroy
with the brightness of his coming.
Even him whose coming is after the
workings of Satan with all power and
signs and lying wonders.
And with all deceivableness of
unrighteousness in them that perish
because they received not the love of
the truth that they might be saved.
And for this cause God shall send them
strong delusion. That they might that
they should believe a lie.
That they all might be
Pay attention what he's saying.
You know, these for because they didn't
like the truth and for this cause God
gave them a strong delusion that they
might believe a lie. That mean they
really believe it now. They think
they're right.
Why did he do this? Go ahead. Finish it
to 12. That they all
that they all might be damned who
believed not the truth
but had pleasure
in unrighteousness.
Do not. That's a reprobate mind. You
didn't lie about the truth when you knew
you was lying. After a while you start
believing. Right.
>> Why is it? Because God turned you over
to a reprobate mind that you might be
damned. You are booked in the lake of
fire. And you don't even
That's all I got to say. Mhm.
What a waste of having the truth.
Okay.
I'm going to move on to our next
question.
Next question, Melon Natural Journey
asks, is manifesting
a sin? And if it is, is it considered
witchcraft?
Is manifesting a sin?
And if it is, is it considered
witchcraft? Brother Dre, what you say?
Uh yes, it depends on what it is that
you manifest.
And how are you manifesting it? A lot of
people
are using vision boards to manifest
things of this world.
But if you if you going about to
meditate on the word
like it says in Psalms 1,
and you meditating on that day and
night, you'll be like a tree planted by
the rivers of water. But
if you are looking to manifest other
things, let's see what the Bible say.
Let's go to Galatians the fifth chapter,
and we going to pick it up at verse 19.
Notice, we talking about manifesting and
the flesh.
Because the flesh is is what and most
people on these boards, they looking to
manifest
things of this world. So let's let the
Bible tell us what it is they
manifesting. Go ahead.
Now the works of the flesh are manifest,
which are these: adultery, fornication,
uncleanness, lasciviousness, idolatry,
witchcraft, hatred, variance, emulation,
wrath, strife, seditions, heresies,
envyings, murders, drunkenness,
revellings,
and such like of the which I tell you
before, as I have also told you in time
past, that they which do such things
shall not inherit the kingdom of God.
I noticed that. In that manifestation of
things, witchcraft is a part of that.
But they dealing with the works of the
flesh, adultery, fornication,
uncleanness.
All of them things mentioned, but
witchcraft is a part of that as well.
Right. Let's go over to Matthew the 6th
chapter right quick.
Matthew 6.
And let's pick it up at verse 19.
Matthew 6 and 19.
Go ahead, brother, when you get there.
Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon
earth,
where moth and rust do corrupt,
and where thieves break through and
steal.
But lay up for yourselves treasures in
heaven,
where neither moth nor rust do corrupt,
and where thieves do not break through
nor steal.
For where your treasure is, there will
your heart be also.
And if your treasure is in the kingdom
of God, that's where your mind will be.
Right.
>> And on your vision board would be
scriptures of the kingdom of God.
Not
cars, houses,
jewelry, and whatever else people
are manifesting. Skip down and read
verse 33, and that'll be it.
But seek ye first the kingdom of God,
and his righteousness, and all these
things shall be added unto you.
So, if you got the kingdom of God and
his righteousness,
And if you get some of those things,
those things won't rule over you because
you got the kingdom of God
as your primary focus.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
I hope that answered their question as
we move on.
Uh moving on. Uh let me ask, what makes
a graven image graven? I have wooden
earrings that are engraved in the image
of a black woman with an afro.
Does it being engraved make it graven?
All right. First of all, what makes a
graven image? Anything that you're going
to set up and say that that's gods. They
got so many of them that they serve in
this world. Statues, pictures, all kind
of things that people put and say that
this is God. But you asked about the
earrings also.
So maybe we can do a two-for-one hit.
Let's go to Exodus the 32nd chapter,
Tangela. Exodus 32.
And show that
earrings was always a part of wear, but
let's see what happened when you cross
the line with those earrings.
Exodus 32 and pick it up at one,
brother, and go ahead and read quickly
for me.
And when the people saw that Moses
delayed to come down out of the mount,
the people gathered themselves together
unto Aaron and said unto him, "Uh make
us gods which shall go before us.
And for as for this Moses, the man that
brought us
out of the land of Egypt, we wot not
what is become of him."
So they say, "Uh make us gods. Forget
the true and living God. We're going to
make some with our own hands." Go ahead.
And Aaron said unto them, "Break off the
golden earrings which are in the ears of
your wives, of your sons,
and of your daughters, and bring them
unto me."
And all the people break off the golden
earrings, which were in their ears, and
brought them unto Aaron.
And he received them out of their hand
and fashioned it with a graving tool.
After he had made it a molten calf,
and they said, "These be the gods, oh
Israel, which brought thee up out of the
land of Egypt." So, they took the
earrings here and gave them to Aaron,
and then he fashioned it and made a
molten calf and said, "This be the gods,
oh Israel, which brought you forth
[clears throat] out of Egypt." So, they
created them a graven image here.
And I know you mentioned about your
earrings, but skip down to verse 7.
Let's see how the Lord felt about that.
Go ahead, Tenzel. The Lord said unto
Moses, "Go, get thee down, for thy
people, which thou broughtest out of the
land of Egypt, have corrupted
themselves." And the Lord was very upset
because he is only true and living God,
and they made a graven image. But let's
turn over to, cuz you asked about your
afro
your afro earrings, but uh that's
nothing new.
Afro Afro earrings was only set when
everybody on this panel had a afro.
And I remember when they used to have
the little picks, Tenzel, that we stuck
in the afro. Sometimes had a little man
on there, too. But that doesn't make it
a god unless you are bending down and
praying to it. But let's go to first
First John, the third chapter. Cuz your
earrings, hey, nothing new. Long as you
ain't worshipping them and making them
out to be something other than a pair of
earrings, you are okay because there's
nothing new with the earrings. First
John 3 and pick it up at verse 4,
brother. Go ahead.
Whosoever committeth sin transgresseth
also the law.
For
is the transgression of the law.
So, saying is a transgression of the
law. And so, your afro pick
and earrings are okay to wear and to use
because we remember them back in the
days of the old when we used to say,
"Power to the people."
All right, that's all I got.
And we're going to move on to our next
question there, Sister Deborah.
Uh yes, next question. Wendy asked, "How
will the people who gather to the
wilderness?
How How will the people be gathered to
the wilderness? And how will we know
when
when to go to the wilderness?"
All right, Brother Jerome, look like we
got a two-part here about gathered and
when to go.
Let's go to um Matthews
chapter 24 and we're going to read verse
31.
We're going to go to Isaiah 60 after
that, Tenzil.
Okay.
You get it, go ahead and read.
And he shall send his angels with a
great sound of a trumpet.
And they shall gather together his elect
from the four winds, from one end of
heaven to the other.
And he say he shall send his angels with
a great sound of a trumpet, that that
seventh trumpet. Mhm. And that's when
the Lord going to gather his elect,
which is the Israel from all over
the world. Let's Let's tie that with uh
you know, and that's that's at the
second coming of the Lord. So, let's
tie that with Isaiah 60.
We're going to read verse 8 and 9.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
Who are these that fly as a cloud, and
as the doves to their windows? Mhm.
Surely the owls shall wait for me, and
the ships of Tarshish first, to bring
thy sons from far,
their silver and their gold with them,
unto the name of the Lord thy God, and
to the holy one of Israel, because he
have glorified thee.
Yeah. So, you have to consider all over
the world,
you know, everybody not going to be
coming being gathered the exact same
way,
using the same means of transportation
all over the world. It's going to be a
multitude of types of transportation to
bring the people,
you know. Right. So, you know, we're in
America, but you got people over there
in Africa, Western Europe, and China,
you know.
The Arctics, you know, so but anyway, uh
let's go to uh the 27th chapter of the
same book.
And read verse
Yeah. Uh
verse 12 and 13.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
And it shall come to pass in that day,
that the Lord shall beat off from the
channel of the river unto the streams of
Egypt.
And ye shall be gathered one by one, all
ye children of Israel.
And it shall come to pass in that day,
that the great trumpet shall be blown,
and they shall come which were ready to
perish in the land of Assyria,
and the outcast of the land of Egypt,
and shall worship the Lord in the holy
mount at Jerusalem.
Mhm.
Now, you know, your other question was,
"How will you know
when to go
to the wilderness?"
We What I What you need to understand is
first there's going to be a fleeing
to the wilderness before the Lord come.
Okay?
And the Lord going to protect his people
in that wilderness for 3 and 1/2 years
during the time of the great
tribulation. When the great tribulation
is over it you're going to have this
great trumpet blow.
Then the Lord going to gather his people
from all over the world.
Okay?
So,
you just understand the the difference
between the fleeing and the gathering.
So,
when the Lord
uh uh uh
uh uh uh uh uh
meet his people in the air, they flee to
that wilderness, you know, and some of
them people going to possibly make the
first resurrection. All right?
But then after the after the Lord come,
then you're going to have a gathering.
Okay?
After the great tribulation, okay?
So,
uh
Can we read
Let me see.
Read that
uh
Did you read Read that verse 15.
24 Matthew 24 and 15.
Matthew 24 and 15. Yeah, it kind of tell
you when to flee.
When you therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet
standing in the holy place,
whoso readeth, let him understand. Go
ahead.
Then let them which be in Judea flee
into the mountains.
Let him which is on the house top not
come down to take anything out of his
house. Mhm. Neither let him which is in
the will in the field return back to
take his clothes. Mhm.
And woe unto them that are with child
and to them that give suck in those
days. Mhm.
But pray you that your flight be not in
the winter neither on the Sabbath day.
Mhm.
For then shall be great tribulation such
as was not since the beginning of the
world to this time.
And no nor ever shall be. Uh.
Are you if you be so blessed you be in
that wilderness you waiting for the Lord
to come. You fled there. All right? Now
the great tribulation let's say is over.
All right? Skip down to verse 29.
And read it to 31.
Immediately after the tribulation of
those days shall the sun be darkened.
And the moon shall not give her light.
And the stars shall fall from heaven.
And the powers of the heavens shall be
shaken. Mhm. And then shall appear the
sign of the son of man in heaven.
And then shall all the tribes of the
earth mourn.
And they shall see the son of man coming
in the clouds of heaven with power and
great glory.
>> Now here come the Lord. That was after
the great tribulation. Keep reading.
And he shall send his angels with the
great sound of a trumpet.
And they shall gather together his
elect. Now you talking about gathering.
Not fleeing. Now you talking about
gathering.
That's after the great tribulation.
Finish it.
From the four winds from one end of
heaven to the other.
That that's all I got. Mhm.
I like to throw it in.
I could throw something in.
Yes. The question was
The first question was asked is when
will we know when to flee?
They're going to build a temple in
Jerusalem.
Yeah. And the pope's going to move in
it. Then the abomination of desolation
will be in the holy place. That's when
you flee. That's right. That's right.
That's right. And then they say, "How
are we going to get there?"
The Lord told you
uh when he went in Isaiah and showed you
that you're going to be by planes and by
ships.
And other scriptures and other places
let you know if you are in the area and
there's a body of water, he's going to
he's going to dry up a river for you to
get there.
But the main thing is when the pope move
into that temple that the going
to build,
flee.
You wonder how you going to get there?
The Lord is going to do like he did
Egypt. He split the Red Sea for Israel.
That means he is going to provide you
transportation
with planes and with ships. All you have
to do is be clean
and be informed enough to know when the
Lord provide this for you. That's all I
have to say. Yeah.
Thank you.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
continue to move on into new territory,
right, Deb?
Uh yes. Uh we are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, February the 11th, 2026.
Uh Sky Rider asked, "Is interracial
marriage okay?"
All right. Is interracial marriage okay?
Guest callers, you want to weigh in on
that?
Well, why don't you go Where is where
the Lord told Israel not to marry
outside of Israel? Can somebody find
that scripture?
Yep. Search mode.
It's in the Kings. Deuteronomy 7.
Can you tell you why? You know, how they
going to take 10 years of life from me?
First Kings 11 is one place.
What does it say? Read it.
Yeah. First Kings 11. Yeah.
Pick out the one where he was telling
Solomon
put all them strange women.
Okay. Pick it up.
Go to Deuteronomy 7. You want to do
that? Okay.
Deuteronomy 7:10. Okay.
And pick it up at verse one.
When the Lord thy God shall bring thee
into the land whether thou goest to
possess it
and have cast out many nations before
thee,
the Hittites and the Girgashites and the
Girgashites
and the Amorites and the Canaanites and
the Perizzites and the Hivites and the
Jebusites, seven nations greater and
mightier than thou.
And when the Lord thy God shall deliver
them before thee that thou smite them
and utterly destroy them,
thou shalt not make no covenant with
them nor show mercy unto them. Neither
shall thou make marriage with them. Thy
daughters thou shalt not give unto his
sons nor his daughters shalt thou give
to that take unto thy sons. Verse four.
For they will turn away thy son from
following me
that they may serve other gods.
So would the anger of the Lord be
kindled against you and destroy thee
suddenly.
That's one place.
Yeah. Now you see that First Kings said
the same thing.
Yeah. And you got some some new in
somewhere in Nehemiah, too. You need
Ezra Nehemiah. Nehemiah 13.
Okay. When you go there?
I think verse 23.
Verse 23, please.
Uh
in those days also saw I Jews that had
married wives of Ashdod and Ammon
and of Moab.
Keep reading.
And the children spake half in the
speech of Ashdod and could not speak in
the Jews' language, but according to the
language of each people. And I contended
with them and cursed them and smoked
certain of them and plucked off their
hair and made them swear by God saying,
"Ye shall not give your daughters unto
their sons, nor take their daughters
unto your sons
or for yourselves.
Did not Solomon king of Israel sin by
these things?
Yet among many nations was there no king
like him,
who was beloved of his God, and God made
him king over all Israel, but
nevertheless even him did outlandish
women cause us to sin.
Shall we then hearken unto you to do all
this great evil
to transgress against our God and marry
strange wives?
Now,
that is what the scripture say.
But then you have an exception.
Back when Moses
married the Ethiopian woman,
what happened when Mo- when Aaron and
and
Miriam complained against him?
I want somebody go there and and read
that cuz he cuz God said something about
Moses that we should pay attention to.
Somebody pull it up.
Yep. Search mode.
Yeah, that's in Numbers, I believe.
Yeah, Numbers 12.
Numbers 12. Mm,
pick it up at 1.
12 and 1.
And Miriam and Aaron spake against Moses
because of the Ethiopian woman whom he
had married, for he had married an
Ethiopian woman.
And they said, "Hath the Lord indeed
spoken only by Moses?
Hath he not spoken also by us?" And the
Lord heard it.
Now the man Moses was very meek above
all the men which were upon the face of
the earth.
And the Lord spake suddenly unto Moses
and unto Aaron and unto Miriam,
"Come out, ye three, unto the tabernacle
of the congregation." And they three
came out.
And the Lord came down in a pillar of
the clouds and stood in the door of the
tabernacle and called Aaron and Miriam,
and they both came forth.
And he said, "Hear now my words.
If there be a prophet among you, I the
Lord will make myself known unto him in
a vision and will speak unto him in a
dream. But my servant Moses is not so.
Who is faithful in all my house. With
him will I speak
mouth to mouth, even apparently, and not
in dark speeches.
And the similitude of the Lord shall he
behold.
Wherefore then were ye not afraid to
speak against my servant Moses?"
And the anger of the Lord was kindled
against them, and he departed.
Go ahead.
And the cloud departed from off the
tabernacle,
and behold, Miriam became leprous,
white as snow.
And Aaron looked upon Miriam and said,
"Behold, she was leprous."
And Aaron said unto Moses, "At last, my
lord, I beseech thee,
lay not the sin upon us, wherein we have
done foolishly,
and wherein we have seen.
All right, so then in this case
he married the Ethiopian woman.
But the difference is Moses was a
faithful servant. Right.
>> So if a faithful
and and you won't let the this strange
person take you away
then you don't have no problem.
Then there's one other case you can deal
with when the when the strange person
make the statement that Ruth made. Will
somebody go to the book of Ruth and read
what she said to Na- to Naomi, her
mother-in-law?
And she told her to go back to her
people in Moab.
Said my people is your people and my
your your God is my God.
Go and read it.
Joshua, Judges, and then Ruth. Joshua,
Judges, and then Ruth.
And that uh first verse, hold on.
Uh read it pick it up where you pick it
up around there.
What verse did you say, brother?
Uh was it 15 or what? Yeah, you um pick
it up at uh 14.
And they lifted up their voices and wept
again. And Orpah kissed her
mother-in-law but Ruth clave unto her.
And she said, "Behold, thy sister-in-law
is gone back unto her people and unto
her gods. Return thou after thy
sister-in-law."
And Ruth said, "Entreat me not to leave
thee
or to return from following after thee.
For whither thou goest I will go.
And whither thou lodgest, I will lie.
Thy people shall be my people and thy
God my God,
with thou dies,
will I die.
And there will I be buried.
So, now, that makes the difference. You
have the two cases with Moses and with
Ruth.
But, God did say,
"Don't marry strangers." That is
scripture. Now, whoever asked the
question,
that's your choice to make.
So, that's the story.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on with the time
check to our next one.
Yes, the time is 8:38.
Mary Higgs asked for you to help her to
see clarity of 1 John 5:15-17.
1 John 5:
15-
17.
Yes, she wants some clarity.
All right. Let's go to brother Chansal.
This is asking
of the Lord. So, let's read that,
brother.
Pick it up at verse 14.
And this is the confidence that we have
in him,
that if we ask anything according to his
will,
he heareth us.
And if we know that he hear us,
whatsoever we ask, we know that we have
the petition that we desire of him.
Mhm. If any man see his brother sin a
sin which is not unto death,
he shall ask, and he shall give him life
for them that sin not unto death.
There is a sin unto death. I do not say
that he shall pray for it.
All unrighteousness is sin. And there is
a sin not unto death.
That's two different That's two
different questions in one question.
You know, and this is the confidence
that we have in him that if we ask
anything according to his will, he hear
it us. And if we know that he hear it
us, whatsoever we ask, we know that we
have the petition that we desire him.
That is based upon if you keep his
commandments. He told you in John 14 and
15, if you love me, keep my
commandments. But then he told you at
John 14 and 14,
if you keep my commandment, then
whatsoever you ask, I will do it.
Now, that answered the first part of
that question.
Somebody want to answer the second part
of it?
Second part is Matthew 12
31 and 32.
Matthew 12
The sin not being forgiven.
Read that when you get there, brother.
Wherefore I say unto you,
all manner of sin and blasphemy shall be
forgiven unto men.
But the blasphemy against the Holy Ghost
shall not be forgiven unto men.
And whosoever speaketh a word against
the Son of man, it shall be forgiven
him.
But whosoever speaketh against the Holy
Ghost, it shall not be forgiven him.
Neither in this world,
neither in the world to come.
Yes, sir.
All right.
We hope that that answered your question
there. We're going to keep moving right
along.
All right. Shane Campbell says, I have a
family member asking me about astral
projection.
I don't know much about it, and how and
how would I answer it in regards to the
Bible?
All right.
Is anyone familiar with this What is
astral projection?
Yes.
Out of body experience.
>> Out of body experience, right?
Well, you know, that is all you know,
that that that is all
a misunderstanding
with with with Paul's writing.
And Paul said he would want to be out of
the body, and he would rather be out of
the body and with God.
But somebody go read that.
Then I'm going to show you what that
means.
All right.
Be there.
Mhm. What is that? Corinthians? Yeah.
Believe it is.
Second Corinthians.
>> 12.
Yeah, Second Corinthians 12.
Is it 5?
>> Let's go there, brother. Tenzel, Second
Corinthians 12 and pick it up at that
verse two.
Are you sure that ain't from Second
Corinthians?
>> No, it's the fifth chapter.
Yeah, fifth chapter.
>> Corinthians 5. 5, yeah. Verse 8.
>> 5. Yeah.
>> First somebody say that. First
Corinthians 5.
5 verse 8.
>> [laughter]
>> All right, we will start at verse 8.
All right, hold on. Guest caller, were
you talking about where he said whether
in the body or out of the body I cannot
tell? No. No, I'm talking about what
Paul was talking about. He wanted to be,
you know, he can he can be
>> the body.
He wanted to be absent He can't He had
to He wanted to be absent from the
rather than with the
>> Oh, okay.
>> Verse 5.
>> Okay, 5 and 8. That's Second Corinthians
5 and 8. Yeah, okay.
Don't you read?
>> I pick it up at verse 6.
Go ahead and read.
So, therefore, we are always confident,
knowing that while as we are at home in
the body,
we are absent from the Lord.
For we walk by faith, not by sight.
We are confident, I say, and willing
rather to be absent from the body, and
to be present with the Lord.
Now,
people saying that see Paul get out of
his body, you know, and from that they
talking about people leaving their body
and looking down on themselves.
Paul is saying, "Look,
really, if you he want to be absent from
the body and present with the Lord." And
you can't but he can.
Why?
Because he is talking about this body
that we are in. Okay? Let's go in the
1st Corinthians the 15th chapter. Let's
show what this is really talking about.
And we're going to start this round uh
verse 49.
1st Corinthians 15 and 49.
And as we have borne the image of the
earthly, we shall also bear the image of
the heavenly.
Now, this I say, brethren, that flesh
and blood cannot inherit the kingdom of
God.
Neither do corruption
>> this.
Listen. That is this body that Paul is
talking about.
We are flesh and blood.
Flesh and blood body cannot inherit the
kingdom of God. Go ahead and read.
Neither do corruption inherit
incorruption.
Uh-huh. Behold, I show you a mystery.
We shall not all sleep,
but we shall all be changed,
in a moment,
in the twinkling of an eye, at the last
trump.
For the trump shall sound, and the dead
shall be raised incorruptible, and we
shall be changed.
For this corruptible must put on
incorruption, and this mortal must put
on immortality.
So, when this corruptible shall have put
on incorruption, and this mortal shall
have put on immortality, then shall be
brought to pass the saying that is
written,
death is swallowed up in victory.
Now, that mean if you have to be
changed, and let's back up a little bit
in where he says,
uh uh uh
some man will say, "What Why are the
dead raised and with what kind of body
will they have?" Let's see where we can
pick that up at.
Mhm. 35.
Okay. Read. We're going to start at 35
and we're going to do a little skipping.
But some man will say, "How are the dead
raised up?
And with what body do they come?"
Thou fool,
thou which thou sowest
is not quickening, except it die.
And that which thou sowest, thou sowest
not that body that shall be,
but bare grain, it may chance of wheat
or of some other grain.
But God giveth
Skip down to verse 44 and continue.
It is sown in natural body.
Read rather and continue.
It is sown in dishonor,
it is raised in glory,
it is sown in weakness,
it is raised in power.
It is sown
It is sown in natural body.
It is raised a spiritual body.
Mhm.
There is a natural body and there is a
spiritual body.
And so it is written, the first man Adam
was made a living soul.
The last Adam was made a quickening
spirit.
Now, the last Adam was the Lord was
Jesus. You know, skip down and read
that.
Uh the first man is
47. Yeah, the first man is of the earth
earthly.
The second man is the Lord from heaven.
So now, all Paul is saying is
if you want to be in the Father's
kingdom
he can't be there in his flesh and blood
body. He have to be absent from this
body
and present with the Lord. Why? Cuz you
have an immortal body. You have a spirit
body. There's a natural body and a
spirit body.
Jesus was called called himself the son
of man.
Right.
And when he come out that grave, he was
indeed the son of God. Go to Romans the
first chapter and start reading at verse
one.
Romans 1 and 1?
Uh-huh.
>> Mhm. And and uh
we going to read a little bit. Go ahead
and start it there.
Paul
a servant of Jesus Christ called to be
an apostle
separated unto the gospel
unto the gospel of God which he had
promised before by his prophet in the
holy scriptures
concerning his son Jesus Christ our Lord
which was made of the seed of David
according to the flesh
and declared
>> now this
Now this is the body that Paul was
talking about.
The body, this body. According to be
made the son of David according to the
flesh. That's the body that we are in
right now. Go ahead.
And declared to be the son of God with
power.
According to the spirit of holiness.
By the resurrection from the dead.
So now when he come up out of the grave
he was no longer the son of David per
se. He was the son
of God.
With power by the resurrection of the
dead. So Paul is simply saying
I want to be absent from this body.
So I can be with the Lord. That's
talking about the father's kingdom.
So there ain't no death in father's
kingdom. There ain't no flesh and blood
in the father's kingdom. So in order for
you to be in that kingdom, you have to
be absent from this body. And you have
to have a flesh and a spirit body to be
with the Lord.
Yeah.
>> I hope y'all understood that.
Yes, sir. In addition to that guest
caller, you gave the biblical answer to
this question. And somebody asking about
astral projection, you are dealing with
a shamanic, Egyptian, and Hinduism,
ancient mysticism religions. Get away
from that. After
out of body experience.
There ain't no out of body experience.
There ain't no out of body experience
unless you God.
Yeah.
On which I
which all on this panel and our viewers
out there, some of them are looking
forward to.
All right. Sister Deborah, with a time
check we'll go
move to our next question. Yes, the time
is 8:51.
Uh Sky Rider asked, is there a biblical
minimum age of marriage.
Open to the panel.
I'm ready anything.
Yeah.
Definitely pay attention to the law of
your state or city of where you are at.
You have some countries who promise
their children
in in wedlock, you know, at a young age.
But he said biblical.
What he got?
Yeah. So, you respond with that 20, I
mean, I
maybe the beginning.
But it said biblical say it.
It didn't say it didn't.
It didn't say it like that.
So, we can't answer.
Well, leave that question as we move on
to our next one.
Next one, Brett Brad asked, is it true
that God puts certain people in your
life path
to potentially help you and or you help
them?
Yeah. Yeah, that's true. That can
happen.
Where is that where we
can read about Philip and the eunuch at?
There you go. Perfect perfect answer.
Where can we go there, uh,
panel?
The Acts. It's Acts.
Acts chapter, I believe.
Acts.
Yeah, 8 and
26.
8 and 26.
Uh, yeah, brother. Pick it up.
Yeah. Acts 8 and 26.
Yep, go ahead, brother. Pick it up right
there.
Go ahead.
And the angel of the Lord speaking to
Philip saying, "Arise and go toward the
south and to the way that goeth down
from Jerusalem unto Gaza, which is
desert."
And he arose and went. Behold, a man of
Ethiopia, an eunuch of great authority
under Candace, Candace, queen of the
Ethiopians,
who had the charge of all her treasures
and had come to Jerusalem for to
worship. Mhm.
>> Returning and sitting in his chariot
reading Isaiah the prophet.
Then the spirit said unto Philip, "Go
near and join thyself to this chariot."
And Philip ran and did overtake him and
heard him read the prophet Isaiah and
said,
"Understandest thou what thou readest?"
There goes some help right here. Go
ahead.
And he said, "How can I except some man
should guide me?"
And he desired Philip that he would come
up and sit with him.
The place of the scripture scripture
which he read was,
"He was led as a sheep to the slaughter
and like a lamb dumb before his
shearers, so he opened not his mouth."
So, we wanted to go there to show that
this brother here needed somebody to
help to help him to understand the book.
And that is what we hope for all of
those who continue to stay tuned in or
looking for the truth. We have it.
Anybody else on the panel?
All kinds of examples in the Bible of
God sending help.
You know, uh Naaman's prophets uh
leprosy was healed.
Often times through the Bible it works
like that.
Yeah, that's right.
And like when Paul was blinded, he told
him to go with and and told and told the
uh uh this guy to go and lay hands on
Paul and he said he's going to uh and
he's going to let Paul know the guy's
name. Who God sent Ananias to lay hands
on him and restore his sight. Once God
had blinded him.
People that are blind all the time.
Yeah. They can make it good or
it's sent from God.
Yeah.
So. Amen.
So. Bless you.
That's right.
That's why Paul said we dealing with
spiritual wickedness in high places.
Mhm.
Yeah.
Find yourself in a place where the truth
be told, pure uncut word of God.
That's it. All right.
We're going to go to our next question,
Deborah. Time is tick-tocking.
Yes, Shaniqua Akou Joby says, "With so
many different melanated skin tones, how
can someone truly know if they are a
Hebrew Israelite?"
All right. Well, I'll tell you what,
like we said earlier in the program, you
tune in
with the next lesson of black history
dealing with slavery and it'll begin to
put you on the right track and give you
some insight on that. Um open to the
panel as well.
Well, the whole thing is
people have the the misconception
that we got all these light people here
because we were mixed with the uh with
with Gentile.
But, you look at the Ethiopians, they
ain't been mixed with nobody. Look at
the Falashas, brother, that come from
Ethiopia. You got dark skin, you got
black skin. Then you got David. But,
David was ruddy colored, wasn't he?
Yeah. Yeah.
Tune in.
How do you know you're Israelite? You
look at your people and see how they got
here.
And what happened to them when they got
And what's happening to it now. Have
nothing to do with the skin tone.
Mhm.
The Lord said Israel
had two meanings. One a speckle bird
that being done other people don't like
you, but then again till you got a
you like a speckle bird and there's more
than one color.
That's Jeremiah 12 and 9 where he calls
us a speckle bird.
Uh-huh.
That's all I got to say.
Yep. All right.
We'll move on to our next question.
Uh next question, be alert
uh asked in Jeremiah 7:29,
are we considered the generation of
God's wrath
because we're still under the curses
from Deuteronomy 28?
Let's go to Jeremiah 7.
Let's pick it up at that verse 29.
And then let's open it up to the panel.
Uh let's pick it up at 28, Kanzel. 28
and 29. Go ahead, brother.
But thou shalt say unto them, This is a
nation that obeyed not the voice of the
Lord their God.
Nor receive correction. Truth is
perished and it's cut off from their
mouth.
Even today. Go ahead.
Cut off thy hair, Jerusalem, and cast it
away and take up a lamentation on high
places.
For the Lord hath rejected and forsaken
the generation of his wrath.
Mhm.
Read 30. Yes, sir.
For the children of Judah have done evil
in my sight, saith the Lord.
They have set their abominations in the
house which is called by my name to
pollute it.
Even today, right, Julius? Yep, this is
talking about Israel.
Israel and Judah.
The whole house.
>> not
it is not just one generation.
It's every generation since the
wilderness.
Yeah.
All right.
We're going to leave it right there,
sister Deborah. One more and then I
think we can call it a evening.
Um
All right, one more.
Uh MC says, "Do I have to keep repenting
about the things I did years ago?"
If you repented
If you repented, you don't have to do it
but one time.
Yes, sir.
>> If you going to do it again, then you
have to repent again. And if the Lord
give you the mind to do it
if he don't cut you off.
Mhm.
Yep. And Repent means do it. Change your
ways.
All right.
Yep. Be be sorry for what you did. Go
ahead, brother.
I said one time and be serious about it.
Yep.
And he said he is not slack concerning
his promises. He is and not deaf and his
arm is not short that he can't save.
Right.
Yep.
Very merciful God that we got there, so
you repent, hey. Let it go. Let it go.
Go and do the same thing that the old
men do. Serve God with all your might.
Can read Ezekiel 18:21 and 22.
Says
mentioned on to you.
Yep.
That's right. Mhm.
Okay.
Sister Deborah, time check.
The time is 9:01.
9:01, okay. We have ran out of time.
And we like to thank everybody who tuned
in with us this evening from all around
the world. And we say if you submitted a
question, we didn't get to it, please
don't resubmit it. Sister Deborah will
take your question and put it in
rotation and we will address that next
week. So, until we all come together
again, please be safe, be blessed, stay
prayed up, and may the Lord have mercy
on us all as Brother Tenzel closes us
out.
Our Father which are in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in
earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the glory forever. In Jesus' name we
pray.
Amen.